A Guide to the Papers of Sarah Patton Boyle, 1949-1970
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Articles and Review by and About Sarah Patton Boyle
  - Miscellaneous material on interracial problems 1955 (Box 26)
  - Magazine articles re South's reaction to desegregation 1955-1959 (Box 26)
  - Commemoration and Christmas stamp for NAACP "50 Year Fight for Freedom" 1959 (Box 26)
  - Material on progress of integration in the South 1960-1961 (Box 26)
  - Articles concerning recent achievements of integration movement 1960-1968 (Box 26)
  - Articles on success of integration 1961 (Box 26)
  - Articles relating to progress of integration movement 1962 (Box 26)
  - Articles on progress of integration 1963 (Box 26)
  - Material on race relations improvement 1965-1966 (Box 26)
  - Articles on Boyle and integration success 1966 (Box 26)
  - Newspaper clippings re Virginia Council on Human Relations and incidents relating to Blacks in Virginia 1954-1960 (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous papers re VCHR 1954-1955 (Box 27)
  - Papers and pamphlets re Kentucky, Louisiana, North Carolina, Florida, and Valparaise University Councils on Human Relations 1964-1965, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Material relating to the formation of Waynesboro Committee on Human Relations 1956 (Box 27)
  - News releases relating to Charlottesville/Albemarle Chapter of VCHR, and TMs carbons of speeches delivered by various people 1956-1957 (Box 27)
  - Material re expenses and accounts for work in VCHR 1956-1957, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Newsletter from VCHR 1956-1965 (Box 27)
  - Pamphlets re VCHR 1958-1960, n.d., Includes eleven TMs carbons and two papers re pamphlets. (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous papers re VCHR n.d. (Box 27)
- Miscellaneous Items
  - Material re polls on attitudes of whites toward blacks 1946-1956 (Box 28)
  - Printed poll sheets. Individual returns of the "Parker Poll" on desegregation run by the School of Sociology, University of Virginia [1957] (Box 28)
  - Material re polls on attitudes of whites toward blacks 1957-1963, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Articles on Boyle and her views on desegregation 1953 Sep-Dec (Box 28)
  - Articles relating to Boyle's civil rights endeavors 1954 Jan-Dec (Box 28)
  - Articles in the Cavalier Daily related to segregation at the University of Virginia 1952 Mar-May (Box 28)
  - Articles on Virginia segregation practices 1951-1952 (Box 28)
  - Articles concerning the desegregation of schools 1947-1954 (Box 28)
  - Materials re Equal Opportunity Employment 1948, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Articles on racism in the North and the South 1949-1952 (Box 28)
  - Materials relating to Florida bombings 1951-1952 (Box 28)
  - Newspaper clippings re desegregation efforts 1951-1964 (Box 28)
  - Material relating to the medical profession attempts at segregation and integration 1952 (Box 28)
  - Articles re Jackson P. Burley School, including one re the death chair sentence for a black rapist 1952 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper articles on discrimination in the North and the South 1952 Jan-Aug (Box 28)
  - Articles on NAACP and desegregation of colleges 1952 Jul 5 & 19 (Box 28)
  - Material relating to Paine College drive for books and pamphlet on the Bethlehem Center; letter, E. C. Peters to Boyle; letter, W. L. Buffington to "Dear Friends" 1952-1953 (Box 28)
  - Anti-Communist and anti-integration newspapers 1954-1960 (Box 28)
  - Articles on Boyle's civil rights endeavors 1955 Feb-Nov (Box 29)
  - Newspaper clippings re Zora Neale Hurston's anti-integration statement 1955 Aug (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets, newspapers, and leaflets of anti-integration nature 1955-1960 (Box 29)
  - Newspaper clippings re Boyle's fight for integration, including several articles on cross-burning 1956 Apr-Nov (Box 29)
  - Partially burned wooden cross [1956]
  - Photograph of cross burning [1956] (Oversize E-6)
  - Material re the League of Women Voters 1956 (Box 29)
  - Printed material and newspaper clippings re John Kasper, anti- integrationist 1956-1958 (Box 29)
  - Articles about Boyle 1957 Jan-Nov (Box 29)
  - Newspaper clippings re Boyle's civil rights opinions and activities 1958 Jan-Nov (Box 29)
  - Articles re desegregation maneuvers in Charlottesville 1958 Jun-Jul (Box 29)
  - Articles re integration movement 1959 Jan-Nov (Box 29)
  - News items and editorials on desegregation 1960 (Box 29)
  - Material re Negro policemen 1960-1961 (Box 29)
  - Articles on Boyle's continued efforts for integration 1963 (Box 29)
  - Articles on Virginia writer's (Boyle's) fight for integration 1964 (Box 29)
  - Articles about Boyle 1965 (Box 29)
  - Newspaper clippings and articles re integration 1965, n.d. (Box 29)
  - Biographical material on Sarah Patton Boyle, with photograph n.d. (Box 30)
  - "The Challenge to the Church," by Aubrey Brown, n.d., TMs carbon, 4 p. (Box 30)
  - Speech by Harry Flood Byrd, "Relative to the Motion to Take Up the So-Called Civil Rights Bill," 1957 Jul 16, TMs, 6 p. (Box 30)
  - "White Virginian Thinks Negroes are Carrying the Banner of Democracy," by Victor Calverton, n.d., TMs carbon, 2 p. (Box 30)
  - Civil Actions Nos. 2435 and 2436, NAACP vs. State of Virginia, Cities of Richmond, Newport News, and Norfolk [1956] (Box 30)
  - Civil Action No. 2657--Briggs et al. vs. R. W. Elliot, et al. Dissenting opinion. Autographed, "To John W. Whetzel with best wishes from J. Waties Waring" [1951] (Box 30)
  - "The County that Closed its Schools: The Story of Prince Edward County, Virginia," Virginia State Advisory Committee to the United States Commission on Civil Rights, 1959-1964, 68 p. (Box 30)
  - Articles on Dr. Tom Dooley--Non-Ugly American ca. 1960 (Box 30)
  - "A Letter to the North," by William Faulkner, Life, with newspaper clipping, February 13, 1957, re Faulkner's arrival at the University of Virginia 1956 Mar 5 (Box 30)
  - "Martin Luther King Memorial Arts Festival" buttons 1970 May 3-9 (Box 30)
  - "Summary of Local Developments [Racial-Legal], Charlottesville, Virginia, September-October, 1968" 1958, TMs (Box 30)
  - Articles on Thurgood Marshall, "A Meeting in Atlanta," New Yorker and "Inside the NAACP" 1956, n.d. (Box 30)
  - "I Sold a House to a Negro," Ebony, by Elizabeth Moore, 1963 Oct, 10 p. (Box 30)
  - Newspaper clippings and flyer advertisements re Rev. Claude J. Murphy, reformed racketeer 1963-1965 (Box 30)
  - "The Law as it Affects Desegregation" by Pauli Murray 1963 Jun 14, TMs (Box 30)
  - "Virginia and the Supreme Court Decision of May 17" by Benjamin Muse 1955 Jan 23, TMs (Box 30)
  - "The Story Nobody Tells You...," McCall's, by William Peters 1958 Sep (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets re blacks and integration 1944-1968 (Box 30)
  - Printed poetry in protest and in affirmation of Civil Rights movement n.d. (Box 30)
  - Material re Poor People's Campaign and voter registration 1959-1968 (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous reports: "Population Characteristics of Augusta, Georgia, 1950" and "Negro Enrollment in Institutions of Higher Learning in the South" 1950, 1952 (Box 30)
  - Factual notes on racial statistics [1947-1952] (Box 30)
  - "The South Reacts to Segregation," The New Leader, by Lillian Smith, n.d., Reprint, 4 p. (Box 30)
  - Papers re Supreme Court Decisions on segregation 1953-1954 (Box 30)
  - "The Threat of War and the Physician's Responsibility" by Souren H. Tashian, M. D., with note, Tashian to Boyle 1957 Jun (Box 30)
  - Booklet, "The University of Virginia Graduation Exercises" 1964 Jun 7 (Box 30)
  - Material re Andrew Young's bid for congressman 1970 (Box 30)
  - "The Vanguard" newspaper 1965 Jan-Feb (Box 30)
  - "Black Boy" by Richard Wright, n.d., AMs, 2 p. (Box 30)
  - "Mississippi's Child" by Gayle Graham Yates, n.d., TMs photostat, 7 p. (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous papers relating to civil rights 1950-1964, n.d. (Box 30)
  - Note cards, envelopes, etc. for organizing Boyle's papers n.d. (Box 30)
- Awards and Citations
  - Citation presented by National Council of Negro Women 1956
  - Citation awarded by Virginia Voters League 1956 (Oversize 1)
  - "Illigitimus Non Carborundum" award presented by local chapter of V. C. H. R. 1956 (Oversize 1)
  - "Russwurn Award" presented by National Newspaper Publishers Association 1958 (Oversize 1)
  - "Citizen's Award" presented by N. A. A. C. P. 1959 (Oversize 1)
  - Citation presented by Local 6, AFL-CIO of New York Hotel and CLub Employees Union 1960 (Oversize 1)
  - Complimentary poem written by Frances Christian Brand 1962 (Oversize 1)
  - "Scroll of Honor" Citation presented by N. A. A. C. P. 1963 (Oversize 1)
  - Certificate of Life Membership in the N. A. A. C. P. 1963 (Oversize 1)
  - "Good American Award" presented by Chicago Committee of One Hundred 1963 (Oversize E-6)
  - "Honorary Award" presented by American Friendship Club 1963 (Oversize 2)
  - "Citizenship Award" presented by the Astoria Beneficial Club 1963 (Oversize 2)
  - Citation presented by the Utility Club, Inc. 1963 (Oversize 2)
  - "Social Action Achivement Award" presented by Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, IOTA SIGMA Chapter 1963 (Oversize 3)
  - "Bishop Ireton Award" presented by Catholic Interracial Council of Richmond 1963 (Oversize 3)
  - Testimonial Citation presented by Quill and Scroll, Jackson P. Burley Chapter 1964 (Oversize 3)
  - "Honor Circle" Citation presented by Mortar Board n.d. (Oversize 3)